focus
innovate
enabled
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
good evening ladies and gentlemen and
welcome to the first episode of the
india risk management awards master
class brought to you by ics alumni
general insurance and cnbc tb18
now as we all know the subtle change
amidst the pandemic has put risk
management at the top of the boardroom
agenda in the past risk management was
often viewed as an exercise in fear and
avoidance this organization is focusing
primarily on completing necessary
compliance driven activities but that's
changing as risk management takes center
stage in this new normal many leaders
are now viewing risks in terms of their
potential to drive performance and value
today's masterclass focuses on the
manufacturing sector and all the lessons
that we have learned in terms of supply
chain risk management now supply chains
have become highly sophisticated and
vital to the competitiveness of many
companies but their interlinked global
nature also makes them increasingly
vulnerable to a range of risks with more
potential points of failure and less
margin of error for absorbing delays and
disruptions forward 19 has illustrated
how many companies may not fully
appreciate their vulnerability to global
shocks through their supply chain
relationships we'll discuss the latest
risk trends in the sector the impact of
the pandemic best risk management
practices to follow and how
manufacturers can mitigate the effects
of forward 19 and prepare for such black
swan events in the future
but before we discuss all of that first
up i would like to welcome mr sandeep
karadya head corporate solutions group
ici affair lombard general insurance to
share his insights into how the pandemic
has added a new layer of complexity to
risk management and how the importance
of risk management has changed
dramatically
as a part of the non-life insurance
sector we have always been working
towards shifting our focus from being a
risk transfer entity to playing a much
more active role as a risk management
partner
taking this initiative forward we
launched the india risk management
awards in association with cnbc tv 18 8
years back
it is a unique platform that honors
organizations that have constantly
evolved and created the best risk
management practices and capabilities
across business categories
kovit 19 has reminded everyone that
pandemic risks are real and capable of
changing a company's risk profile
quickly
it has had a truly global impact where
many supply chains have been severely
impacted for example component suppliers
to the automobile industry even the fmcg
industry has got severely impacted due
to the last mile connectivity issues
the market conditions reveals that the
businesses have been severely impacted
due to overt related you know challenges
despite government assurances
over the past year the business
landscape has become much more complex
due to the uncertainty towards pandemic
response
vaccine rollouts and emerging virus
variants which keeps on having an impact
on different types of risks
addressing such risk is a clear
challenge for today's risk managers
given that these risks have no history
they are widespread and they keep on
taking new reforms as companies seek to
strengthen their operations the
importance of supply chain resilience
and robust risk management is much more
apparent than ever before
we have seen various steps being taken
by various organizations such as
increasing investments in technology to
ensure sustainable
uh supply chain
advances in artificial intelligence and
blocked interior blockchain technologies
present opportunities for digitization
of the supply chain
while organizations have embraced the
new normal radically changing and
existing supply chain is also not easy
companies will need to undertake a
holistic analysis such as moving supply
chains nearby or to different countries
in order to reduce dependency as well as
consideration
this would help to create a much more
sustainable operations for the future
moving forward in such a high risk
environment the role of risk management
professionals has changed dramatically
and brought risk to the center of earth
to the center stage
with this in mind we at ics rumbard are
confident that today's session with our
expert panel will provide each one of
you relevant insights for risk
management to drive sustainable growth
for respective organizations
thank you and i hope that you have a
great session ahead
thank you sally for those valuable
insights next i would like to invite our
keynote speaker for the evening
managing director bridgestone india to
share with us the top risk factors which
impact the supply chain of manufacturers
he will also share bridgestone india's
risk management strategies which were
deployed to identify and manage supply
chain risks during the pandemic the
kovitt crisis has been very broad-based
started with health affected travel
businesses suffered huge revenue loss
and we are seeing now how the supply
chains are disrupted so what's the key
to manage
the risks and thrive in such a dynamic
situation
let's start by understanding what the
situation has been
it has been truly vuca
v stands for volatile
or volatility u for uncertainty c for
complexity and a for ambiguity so it has
been a truly vuca time in the whole
world over the last two years
to counter this
businesses have to have vision to
counter the volatility
have to have a deep understanding of
their surroundings
to cut through the uncertainty
they need clarity
to really understand what is important
for their business so that they can
reduce complexity
and i think the most important thing is
agility
in an ambiguous world agility is very
very important
so i believe companies who are able to
demonstrate this agility have not only
survived but actually they have thrived
in this
in this challenging times
i'm fortunate to have been part of a
team at bridgestone india who have
emerged much stronger as a business
after this crisis
so i'd like to leave you with a couple
of final thoughts
kovit has been a big big crisis a big
challenge
and this was unexpected
but
i do not believe this is the last big
crisis that we will have to deal with
we don't know where the next big crisis
will come from and what nature it will
have
but one thing is for sure there will
definitely be such challenges in the
upcoming years
what we have learned through this crisis
the importance of agility the importance
of
adapting to the situation very very
promptly
will hold us in good state also in
future crisis
so this is the lesson we are taking from
the covet crisis
and hopefully this is what will help
businesses like us and yours to continue
to thrive also in future situations
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
icrci lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
next up we have our panel discussion so
i would like to welcome our esteemed
guest for the evening starting with mr
aloha gal executive director of icici
and lombard general insurance
mr divyar maniksha jivasha global head
and president of sr group
mr anil chopra group head
coe of apollo tires
and mr abhay ghetto cfo of jumble
fertilizers gentlemen thank you so much
for joining us on this panel discussion
which is going to focus on the lessons
from covet 19 for supply chain risk
management
with the particular focus on the
manufacturing sector so uh aloof uh you
know let me start with you um you know
it's been almost two years actually
since the kobe 19 uh pandemic and there
were a lot of learnings at the beginning
of the curve to where we are now um just
a few thoughts in terms of what were the
key risk trends which were highlighted
particularly for the manufacturing
sector as you went through this learning
curve so to speak so if you look at the
manufacturing sector
uh there were two different phases one
was the initial phase of the
lockdown and then when unlock happened
then the second phase started initially
it was all about safety of the people
and digital transformation of the
company basically how to make people
work from home as well as if there are
workers who have how to get them to work
as well as make it safe for them to work
and they were
along with it there was a weaker demand
happening there was a supply chain
disruption happening because the
movement of goods was not free there was
a raw material shortage happening there
was a low capacity utilization so there
were a number of problems that were uh
uh were there in the initial phases of
uh lockdown when the unlock started and
the demand started picking up a new set
of problems that emerged and the biggest
problem that he was after that was the
supply chain disruption uh problem and
the shortage of labor because the the
labor suddenly became a pla
by the case that our labor was a scarce
commodity and and where people were
unable to get the people back from their
villages so if they in the both the
phases you see there were different sets
of problems but going forward i would
say that the second set of problems is
going to remain for a while before we
are able to solve it
in fact let's go with those set of
problems are getting across the sector
which is really beleaguered and
continues to be so and that's the auto
industry anil uh let me come to you with
the the query here in terms of in terms
of code and the impact it's had on the
auto industry particularly the auto
ancillary space
you know what do you think the learnings
were and most importantly how has
industry sort of reoriented itself to
address some of these
fresh challenges which are unlikely to
go away
as alok rightly mentioned
we were
faced with a sudden
lockdown situation
uh so
everything just came to a grinding halt
but uh
let me also add that there were
indications that started coming from
china you know a couple of months before
that things were uh not uh not okay
there
and therefore as as a proactive measure
our procurement team started shifting
some of the
supplies
from
neighboring countries like vietnam
cambodia and even started tapping the uh
the european vendors
to to get the supplies in
and that really helped uh you know to to
at least fight over the first two months
of the problem that we saw coming
uh but when uh you know when the entire
country went into a lockdown then there
was a there was a different problem
there was a surplus inventory which we
didn't know what to do with and they
were so there were more coming on the
way on the ships
so so our next challenge was to stop
them
to to defer them
and you know if possible uh divert them
somewhere else
and also uh the another big problem was
to to extend the credit period because
suddenly cash flow became came to a halt
now let me come to insurance and
particularly i look to your company i
mean looking at the scale and size of
your business um
you know what is it that uh you did as a
company in order to sort of reorient and
uh you know rework your strategy when it
came to some of these challenges during
the pandemic now digital transformation
is a very vast subject and it has to be
done in every piece of our business for
example if we have to issue the policy
it has to be done digitally and there
the regulator comes into play luckily
the regulator allowed us to issue the
policy digitally
then for booking of the policy the
entire system had to work from home so
people had to be supplied laptops at
home whereas the senior people almost
all of them had a laptop at home
relatively junior people some of them
did not have laptops and at that time
there was a scarcity of laptop being
available in the market so that also had
to be a year where i had to be supplied
the third problem is that the front line
people say the call centers was
also had to operate the call center
people most of them could operate only
from the offices we had to supply them
with laptops and the connectivity at
home so that they could can answer to
each and every question of the customers
so this is a digital and then fourth
people were getting accustomed to
selling out to buying policies only
online so all products had to be online
and they were they had to be we had to
have underwriting flexibility to be
given that all products can be sold
online so that was the entire digital
transformation journey that had to be
done
so i think what we're hearing is a
common set of challenges uh about having
a strong balance sheet about you know
the digitization challenge managing on
ground logistics okay
if i can come to you now in terms of the
fertilizer space and jumble fertilizers
our stock has been you know
handsomely rewarded by the stock markets
for its performance but
how did you sort of take some of these
challenges head on what were some of the
biggest problems you faced and how did
you overcome it first thing that we did
was to protect our personnel because we
have a continuous process industry we
have people staying inside the plants
and most of our
loading unloading labor is basically
outsourced and they are contractors
so we have to create a big bio bubble to
keep them in the place and we knew that
they could not go out because if
they did they could contact the disease
so keeping almost
800 people in a campus designed to keep
only 400 or 500
was a big challenge and we had to set up
a temporary hospital
uh or a quarantine center also some
distance away so that we could rotate
people in and out that was strictly
controlled that was the first thing that
we did
as mr chopra said there was an inkling
of things that would go bad so we
started doing some trial runs with our
personnel and working from home even
before the government
had announced the lockdown most of our
people are fitted out with laptops so
that wasn't the problem but the problem
was the bandwidth
and getting people to start working
seamlessly on our erp systems
along the way we also realized that we
are very vulnerable to cyber attacks
because i read somewhere that boeing had
a big problem because of a very very big
number of people working from outside
and they got caught with some ransomware
issues
so we have to immediately scale up
our
conferencing systems and also our
cyber security systems very quickly
fortunately we found the resources to do
that so let me come across uh to you
dania because you know as a conglomerate
you would have so to speak to borrow uh
you know uh the analogy there from uh
from up here several snakes in your
backyard uh you know how did you as a
group sort of uh
approach some of these risks so was it a
one solution fits all or did you sort of
uh navigate and create specific
solutions for each of the challenges you
faced in each of your verticals for each
of our
industries for we are depending on the
geographies like our refinery in the
united states uh sorry in the united
kingdom or our
other manufacturing units in india we
have to take a different stand and
support the other
everybody has visited the occasion in
some way or the other but the fact of
the matter is that this is the time when
really one realizes something which
nobody ever has done seriously and
looked at it as a tick box
and that is risk management
according to me most companies are not
serious about risk management how many
of us can actually say that we have got
a centralized function which coordinates
with the other functions and ensures
that in terms of crisis there are key
decision makers who will take the
decisions which will keep the plans or
which will keep the operations running
smoothly so while we can say all this
the time has come when the risk
management management should be taken at
board level and the board should look at
it seriously and they themselves should
be personally involved so that people
down the line take this seriously you
see what we have seen is that whatever
action which everybody is talking about
was basically fragmented i don't think
anybody was working very honestly to a
cohesive plan where everybody was
working in sync and what we now realize
is the importance of a digital world and
when we when we talk of digital world we
also need to remember the the
disadvantages of it like today's cyber
hacking i mean what is the cypher uh you
know security of which the team and the
company has
what about you know when this thing
happened out of 500 fortune companies
more than 163 companies had that tire
one supplier from china
now
we are talking only tire one what about
a tire two supplier also
when we look at this tire one and tire
two suppliers what we see is that there
was disruption and it was only companies
who had a strong risk management
techniques
which were able to survive is better
than the other that were able to get
into the rhythm faster than most who did
not have that
so my take on this whole thing was is
that one should have a strong risk
management division they should have the
right people people at the top should
take this function seriously especially
in the manufacturing industry which is
group which many people look at this as
a tick box
indeed and that's exactly what we don't
want to do because uh kovic sort of hit
after all i think uh like a bolt from
the blue across all industries so i look
you know in taking that very important
point that denyer said in terms of risk
management because rather than fire
fighting how are companies and for
instance yours preparing for the future
because uh you know this is one notable
pandemic many more are likely to come
we're talking about climate change and
that is likely to evolve into all sorts
of press challenges for humanity as a
company
how are you sort of reorienting for the
future for this new normal because
things are never going to go back to
what they were like are they uh
now to monitor them and they're not only
to find out where they are located but
care also to use it
as a as a supply chain management tool
is a is an important step for example
there is a client of ours in the middle
space
who is using our
our tracking system of trucks through
these gps chips for just in time
inventory management so they know that
within the next four hours this truck is
going to arrive and therefore
my supply is going to come and in case
there is an accident or something like
that and that is going to be delayed
they are alerted in advance and they
have to make alternate arrangements and
and so that the supply keeps
uninterrupted now as far as our company
is concerned we we are basically uh also
basically uh we are providing another
solution called risk index
we uh as mr vinya mentioned that there
are very few companies in india who have
a body which is reporting to the board
which is assessing the various risks in
advance and not reacting only at the
time of the event happening and and
basically we are creating a proactive
solution so this risk index is basically
measuring a company across six risk
broad risk parameters and 32 detail
these parameters and comparing their
risk
preparedness versus what is the reaction
at a time at the time of risk event
happening
this risk index will then give a
benchmark the company against the other
peers in the industry
so this way every company in the
industry knows where it stands and and
can take a really proactive measure such
that they improve their positions
gentlemen thank you so much for joining
us on this the master class session
about some of the challenges that the
manufacturing sector has been uh facing
as far as supply chain
issues are concerned in this post-covet
world
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards risk master
class
focus
innovate
enable